让我来
Here,let me do it
先按下号码 然后刷卡
Put your number in,then your card
你的号码是多少 罗蓝
What's your number,Roland
Three fifteen
看 多么容易
See how easy it is
- 引擎效率  - 94%
- Engine efficiency   - 94 percent
我们需要更多
We need more
支持压力如何
- How's the back pressure
你认为怎样  它不断上升
- What do you think  - It's climbing
增加风叶倾斜度
Increase the blade inclination
我说增加风叶倾斜度
- I said, increase the blade inclination
风叶倾斜度是派除以9
- Inclination is pi over nine
我们已经到达最大速度
We've reached maximum velocity
不行
No
放手去做   一定做得到
Let it go,it will work
引擎会毁掉 我才不干
The engine'll destroy itself,I won't do that
不会毁掉的 做吧 快完成了
It's not going to destroy itself.Come on,we're almost there
我们的方程式有点错误
- Something's wrong with our equations
发生什么事
- What happened
没事 因为瑟诺拉了开关
- Nothing,because Surnow pulled the plug
我只是保护机器
- I'm protecting the baby
四年来的工夫 法兰克
- And four years of work, Frank
四年的功夫等于零
- four years of work that's going to add up to zilch
除非我们有进展
because unless we show some progress
不然我们就别干了 朗
they're going to pull the plug on us,Ron
他说的对 你应该继续测试
He's right,you should've continued the test
有人可以达到15马赫 而我希望那就是我们
Someone'll crack Mach 15,I want it to be us
我不是故意阻碍
I won't jeopardize everything
只是因为你们两人 等不及要出名
because you two can't wait to see your name in print
出名才有钱 朗
It's the print that gets the money,Ron
如果你想玉石俱焚 好 去吧
If you want to go down in flames together,fine,You go ahead
我要去计算程式
I'm going to do the math
晚安 奇斯博士
Good night,Dr.Keats
搞什么
What the hell
罗蓝 开门
Roland,open the door
开门 罗蓝
Open the door,Roland,
我要你小心听着
I want you to listen to me very carefully
我们要打开这道门 罗蓝 不要乱来
We have to open this door,Roland,Stop typing
罗蓝
Roland
罗蓝 开门
Roland,open the door
你在做什么
What are you doing
开门
Open the door
罗蓝 你听到了吗
Roland, are you listening
啊    不
Aagh  No
婚礼如何
- How was the wedding
新郎昏倒那部分
- The part where the groom passed out
还是狗咬鼓手那段
- Or the dog bit the Dr.ummer
你接到新娘丢的捧花吗
- Did you catch the bouquet
可能有吧
Maybe
所以你不能在电话谈吗
So is that what you couldn't talk to me about over the phone
每个人说不存在 计划是存在的
The project they say doesn't exist does exist
伊卡鲁斯计划
- The Icarus Project
下一代喷射引擎的设计
- The next generation in jet engine design
速度是两倍燃料却只要一半
Capable of doubling speeds using half the fuel
起码在理论上
At least in theory
朗 瑟诺是航太专家
And Ronald Surnow was an aeronautical scientist
在大学研究这个项目
who worked on it here at the university
是的 关系多密切
- Yes  - How close are they
我不确定 但瑟诺是研究小组
I'm not sure, but Surnow's the
六个月内第二个死去的科学家
second scientist to die in the last six months
好的 但这跟X档案有何关系
OK.But how is this an X-File
穆德 你不认为 这事与幽浮技术有关吧
Mulder,you don't think this is about UFO technology
有些事无法解释 史卡利
There's something unexplainable here, Scully
但肯定不是无法辨别
but certainly it's notnot unidentifiable
奇斯  在那边
- Keats   - There
奇斯博士
Dr.Keats
我们是联邦调查局探员
We're with the FBI
我是穆德探员 这是史卡利探员
I'm Agent Mulder,This is Agent Scully
我们知道你今早发现瑟诺博士
We understand you discovered Dr. Surnow this morning
所留下的残骸
What was left of him
你认为他如何被困于风洞内
How do you suppose he became trapped in the wind tunnel
一定有人把门锁住
Someone must have shut him in
这门只能由内开或锁上
- The door is operated from there
透过电脑控制
- By computer
我已向警察报告过到底要讲几次
We've already been through this with the police How many times do we have to reheaded
你的研究小组近期 有另一名成员也死了
Another member of your team died recently,isn't that correct
是的 亚瑟 葛瑞柏
Yes,Arthur Grable
他在11月死于车祸
He was killed in an automobile accident in November
我叫法兰克 诺勒特 也在这计划工作
I'm Frank Nollette,I'm also on the project
你肯定这是意外  你在怀疑什么
- Are you certain it was an accident   - What are you Dr.iving at
你们的工作看来是 工业间谍最好的目标
Your work seems to be a perfect target for industrial espionage
这是谁写的
Who wrote this
当我走时 朗还在工作
Ron was working on it when I left
你看这里的字迹
The handwriting here doesn't
看来与其他的字迹不吻合
seem to match any of the other handwriting
不是我的
It isn't mine
是罗蓝 富勒
What about Roland Fuller
罗蓝  只是清洁工
Uh,Roland's the,janitor
根据警方报告
According to the police report,
昨晚他是唯一在这里的人
he was the only other person here last night
不会是罗蓝写的  你怎么知道
- Roland didn't do that  - How do you know
罗蓝不是火箭科学家
Let's just say Roland isn't exactly a rocket scientist
看看
Here
崔西
Tracy
有星星
With stars
罗蓝
Roland
这里有些人想与你谈谈
There are some people here would like to talk with you
啊  哦
Uh-oh
我纸用完了
I went off the paper
对不起 没问题 罗蓝
- Sorry  - That's all right, Roland
崔西
Tracy
到视讯房帮我好吗
Would you like to come help me in the TV room
没问题
Ok
你好 罗蓝 我们可以坐下吗
Hi,Roland  Mind if we sit down
谢谢
Thanks
介不介意问你几个问题
Do you mind if we ask you a couple of questions
你记不记得昨晚工作的事  啊 哈
- Do you remember working last night   - Uh-huh
记不记得看到了不寻常的事
Do you remember seeing anything unusual
看到任何陌生人
Seeing any strangers
那么
Did,um
瑟诺博士或奇斯博士
Did Dr.Surnow or Dr. Keats
或是诺勒特博士 有任何不寻常的事
Or Dr.Nollette do anything unusual
没有
Nope
你一定很喜欢星星
You must like stars
147个
One hundred and forty-seven
对不起   星星
- Sorry  - Stars
你也喜欢数字 哈
You like numbers,too  huh
罗兰 我来帮你
Roland, let me help you
1  2
One  two
Three
4  5
Four  five
Six
7  8 罗蓝 你没事吧
- Seven eight   - Roland, is everything OK
9  10 罗蓝 你没事吧
nine,ten  Roland, are you all right
Eleven
12  13  发生了什么事
- Twelve  thirteen  - What happened
你们说了什么令他不安
What did you say to upset him so
Sixteen
Seventeen
这肯定是第四者写的
It's definitely the work of a fourth individual
瑟诺博士 奇斯博士 和诺勒特博士的字迹
Dr.Surnow's, Dr.Keats' and Dr.Nollette's cursive standards
跟你们在白板所发现的不同
don't match what you found on the white board
你能帮我看看这个吗
Will you do me a favour and try this
是什么
- What is it
罗蓝在家中乱画乱写的纸
- Something Roland was doodling at home
你真的不认为罗蓝
- You don't really think Roland
除了诺勒特和奇斯
Besides Nollette and Keats,
我们能够证实他 是昨晚唯一在实验室的人
- He was the only other person in the lab
对 但是我们谈论的是
But we're talking about a
流体力学方程式的问题
sophisticated fluid dynamics equation
罗蓝的智商只有70
Roland Fuller barely has an IQ of 70
你见过他的数学能力
You saw his facility with math
独立运算显示极其不寻常
Don't some autistic individuals display unusual abilities
对 但即使专家的行为 只作为人类的计算机
Yes,but even savants behave only as human calculators I mean
我意思是他们能表现一些功能
They can perform certain functions
但他们不能说出事物的价值
but they can't tell you the value of anything
或甚至数字的意思
or the  meaning of a number
我讨厌偏袒 但底线是否定的
I hate to take sides guys,but the bottom line is no
6的末端 5的开头
The terminal stroke on the six, the roof on the five
对不起 不是他写的
I'm sorry,he didn't write it
啊
Aagh
有机体曝露在液态氮里
An organic object exposed to
零下320度会冰封
liquid nitrogen at minus 320 degrees will become frozen
展现很大的拉力
Exhibiting great tensile strength
但经过压缩或碰撞容易受破坏
but is vulnerable to stress from compression or impact
我以前见过鱼的示范
Now I've seen this demonstrated on a fish before
我不认为
I don't think
他们会在"怪头博士" 的节目里进行这实验
they'll do this on Beakman's World
指纹取了吗
Has this been dusted
请用 谢谢
- Treat yourself  - Thanks
史卡利 来看看这些档案
Hey, Scully,look at these files
"KMAN"应该是指奇斯
KMAN must be Keats
他的档案于 昨晚12点31分关闭
This file was turned off at 12 31 last night
看看 还有人进入档案
But look  Someone else entered
名叫"亚瑟" 在12点31分之后
a file under the name ARTHUR after 12 31
一直工作几乎有五个小时
and worked on it for nearly five hours
这不可能是奇斯
Well, it couldn't have been Keats
根据尸体判断
Judging from the rigor of the body,
他大约在12点30分死亡
he was dead around 12 30
你是说 有人进来把奇斯杀了
So someone came in killed Keats
继续研究亚瑟 葛瑞柏博士的旧档案
and then just did some work on an old Dr. Grable file
我不能进入亚瑟档案 我们需要密码
I can't access the ARTHUR file,we'll need the password
试试15626
Try 15626
你怎么知道
How did you know that that
这是亚瑟葛瑞柏的研究
This is Arthur Grable's work
同样的动力方程式 其他人正在研究
on the same equations the others were working on
看看那些输入
Look at all those entries
从他死后 有人继续他的研究工作
Someone has been continuing his work since he died
你怎么知道密码的
How did you know what the password was
挥手再见 挥手再见
Wave goodbye    Wave goodbye
挥手再见 再见
Wave goodbye    Bye-bye
挥手再见
Wave goodbye
罗蓝
Roland
为何昨晚你穿工作服睡觉
Why did you sleep in your clothes
我帮你拿衣服 有人来找你
Well,let's get you dressed,you have visitors
我不应该跟他们谈话
I'm not supposed to talk to them
谁跟你说的
Who told you that
记得我教过你吗
Remember that talk we had
不要害羞
about being shy
他们是好人 罗蓝
These are nice people,Roland
罗蓝 你的衣服比我多
Hey,Roland,you've got more shirts than I do
我认为这件很时髦 你认为如何
This one would look stylin' today  What do you think
绿色那件 绿色
- The green one  - The green one
请
Please
史托迪太太 我可和你谈一会吗
Mrs Stodie, can I talk to you a second
待会见 罗蓝
See you later, Roland
这件
This one
拿着
There you go
你喜欢在大学的工作吗 罗蓝   喜欢
- Do you like your job at the college, Roland   - Yes
听说你做得很好
I hear you're very good at it
你怎么取得这份工作的
Do you remember how you got your job
有人跟史托迪太太说的
A man talked to Mrs Stodie
什么人
What man
葛瑞柏博士
Dr.Grable
博士对你很好吗
Was Dr.Grable nice to you
是的
Yes
上次你跟他谈话是什么时候
When did you last speak to him
上星期  前天
Last week,the day before
葛瑞柏博士死了
Dr.Grable died
对不起
I'm sorry
人死了
People die
他们都消失
They go away
他们不应该再回来
And they're not supposed to come back
罗蓝有提到亚瑟这个名字吗
Has Roland ever mentioned the name Arthur
那是葛瑞柏博士的名字
That was Dr.Grable's first name,
但我们叫他葛瑞柏博士
but we only called him Dr.Grable
我看罗蓝根本不知道 他的名字叫亚瑟
I doubt Roland even knew his first name was Arthur
史托迪太太
Mrs Stodie,
可否给我 罗蓝的档案和病历副本吗
can I get a copy of Roland's file and past history
病人的资料是保密的
- Our patients' histories are confidential
我明白 但我有权取得
- I understand, but I can obtain them
越少时间花在法庭上
The less time we spend in court,
我们就有越多时间帮助罗蓝
the more time we have to help Roland
罗蓝 富勒是亚瑟 葛瑞柏雇用的
Roland Fuller was hired by Arthur Grable
他去中途之家
He specifically wanted a
特意找一个智力有缺陷的人
mentally challenged person
你是说亚瑟 葛瑞柏
Are you suggesting Arthur Grable
雇用罗蓝 是为了利用他
hired Roland in order to use him
你是说亚瑟 葛瑞柏没死
Are you suggesting Arthur Grable is not dead
如果他意图杀害 诺勒特 奇斯和瑟诺
If he had intentions of killing Nollette, Keats and Surnow
为何不安排嫌疑犯
why not set it up to appear the least likely suspect
是的 照这样看来 他跟汉堡一样
But, by the look of this, he's hamburger
也许是他安排的
Maybe he staged it
这解释了他"死"了六个月
that would explain why his work is continuing on,
他的工作仍然继续进行
six months after his    death
报告上写亚瑟葛瑞柏
This obituary says Arthur Grable
在西雅图出生 父亲是个大银行家
was born in Seattle  His father was a big banker
母亲乐于从事慈善活动
his mother was active in a number of charities
独子 专修物理
only child  Summa cum laude in physics
博士和博士后研究 主修航空工程
Doctoral and postdoctoral
在哈佛大学毕业
in aeronautical engineering at Harvey Mudd
前途无量 英年早逝
Brilliant future tragically cut short
罗蓝也是西雅图出生
Roland's also from Seattle
他一生的大部分时间 都在中途之家
He spent most of his life at the Heritage Halfway House
他父母的身份被管制
The identity of his parents has been sealed
罗蓝三岁前的资料很少
There's very little information
三岁那年被送到中途之家
before the age of three, when he went to the home
他何时出生
does it say when he was born
1952年7月15日
July 15, 1952
跟亚瑟出生日期一样
That's also Arthur's birth date
难道你不希望你能飞吗
Don't you wish you could fly
我可以
I can
当我做梦的时候
When I dream
人在梦里什么都能做
people can do anything in a dream, you know
有一次
Once
我梦见我们结婚
one time I had a dream we were married
住在一起
and lived in a house
你有做梦吗 罗蓝
Do you have dreams, Roland
你可以告诉我
you can tell me
罗蓝
Roland
谁是亚瑟
Who's Arthur
啊
Aagh
对不起 罗蓝
I'm sorry, Roland
对不起
I'm sorry
罗蓝
Roland
走开
Go away
罗蓝 怎么了
Roland
走开
Go away
我不想伤害你
I don't want to hurt you
走开
Go away
那个是你吗   对
- Is that you   - Yes
酷
Cool do
有故事吗
What's the story here
啊
Um
我的量子物理教授
A quantum physics professor
在哈佛大学读书时 啊 把我当了
of mine at Harvey Mudd,uh,flunked me
他不赞同我的理论
He challenged a tenet of one of my theories
后来我把理论 拿到"自然期刊"出版
A theory I later published in Nature
总之 要报复他一番
Anyway, uh,to get back at him
一个下午 我们决定拆了他的车
One afternoon we decided to take his car apart
在他办公室
And put it back together
再恢复原状并且发动车子
again in his office, and left it running
典型的知识分子
- Mmm  An egghead classic
这是亚瑟 葛瑞柏的主意
- It was Arthur Grable's idea
坐在椅子上的 是亚瑟 葛瑞柏吗
- Is that Arthur Grable sitting on the chair
对
- Yeah
他喜欢搞笑吗
- Was he a practical joker
比他的聪明才智还更高竿
- Atop of all his brilliance
他在精心策划方面是个天才
He had a genius for elaborate schemes
你看他有办法让人以为
Could he be making it seem
一个智商70的人
like a man with a 70 IQ is gaining access to
进入并操作他的旧档案吗
And, uh    operating his old computer files
那也要亚瑟还活着才行
Arthur would still have to be alive
他会不会是假死   不
- Could he have faked his own death   - No
警察在车祸的报告指出
The police report on the auto accident
葛瑞柏死无全尸
was that killed Grable is woefully incomplete
在干地面上 没有机械故障问题
A dry road surface  No mechanical problems
尸体没有送去停尸间
The body was never admitted
而且没有举行葬礼
to a county morgue and there was no funeral
如果你是猜测
If you are trying
亚瑟 葛瑞柏杀了瑟诺和奇斯
to suggest that Arthur Grable
然后下一个是我
killed Surnow and Keats, and is after me next
那你大可放心
you're way off
亚瑟不可能这样做
Art could not have done the murders
你怎么能如此肯定
How can you be so certain
这个就是亚瑟 葛瑞柏
This is Arthur Grable
汽车意外
Because of massive damage to his body
令他内部严重受伤
caused by the car accident
因此我们只能保留头部
we could only preserve the head
难道你的客人在未来解冻后
Wouldn't your client find it inconvenient
才发现他无法行动
to be thawed out in the future,
不会感到不方便吗
only to discover he had no functional mobility
我们相信在那时候的科学
we believe that by the time science figures a way
能找到方法让我们的客人复活
to revive our clients
你也知道 怎样为他们复制新的身体
- You'll also know how to clone new bodies
没错
- Exactly
这种技术
This technology is progressing
比其他人想像中发展的还快
faster than anyone thought possible
去问大学里的任何人
Ask anyone here the university
每过一会儿 时间一秒秒过去
while for us
我们的身体就越接近死亡
the passing of each second brings our bodies closer to death
而我们的客人 就越接近重生
for our clients it brings them closer to life
这些温度的变化经常发生吗
These fluctuations in temperature  do they happen often
不 只有葛瑞柏博士 这个密封装置有些问题
We've had some problems with Dr. Grable's capsule
我们的技术员已经检查过 但是没有发现故障
Our technicians checked it temperature fluctuations and found nothing
会不会是脑子影响波动
Is it possible the brain is causing it
不
No
但我们正寻找答案
But we are looking for the explanation
这个病人没有危险
The patient's in no danger
只要有液态氮在容器里
He remains perfectly preserved
他在密封装置里仍然保存良好
as long as there's liquid nitrogen in the capsule
我们可以看看亚瑟 葛瑞柏的资料吗
May we take a look at Arthur Grable's records
谢谢
Thank you
贝灵顿博士 以你未来医学科学的观念
Dr.Barrington,as to future medical science
以后的器官捐赠 会有什么条件
what requirements will exist to be an organ donor
有些跟今天的要求一样
Same as today
最好有兼容性基因
- compatible genetic make-up
如果有亲属关系就最好
It's best if the donor's related
穆德
Mulder
亚瑟 葛瑞柏只写下一名捐献人
Arthur Grable put down only one donor
罗蓝 富勒和亚瑟 葛瑞柏同一天出生
Roland Fuller and Arthur Grable have the same birthday
我想他们是双胞胎
I think they're twins
老一点还是年轻点
Older or younger
同年 只是头发少一点 视力好一点
Same age  Just less hairy and with better eyesight
是 还有胡子呢
- Gotcha  And the moustache
不 不要胡子
- No,lose the whole beard
然后呢
Next
短发往后梳高
Close-cropped hair,with a slightly receding widow's peak
不要眼镜
Lose the glasses
那就是罗蓝 瘦或胖个几磅
- That's Roland  - Give or take a few pounds
告诉我你的梦 罗蓝
Tell me about your dreams,Roland
没问题 我不会告诉别人
It's all right,I won't tell anybody
你知道 我昨晚有个梦
You know,I had a dream last night
我做梦在游泳池游泳
I dreamt I was swimming in this pool
我能在水底看到我父亲
And I could see my father underwater
但我潜下去 水刺到我的眼睛
But when I dove down,the water stung my eyes
在游泳池还有一个男人
And there was another man at the pool,
看着我
watching me
他令我不安
He upset me
他问我问题而我不想回答
He was asking me questions I didn't want to answer
我就离开了
I had to leave
我还是找不到我父亲
I couldn't find my father
我不能对你说我的梦
I can't tell you my dreams
为什么
Why not
不好
Bad
是你的梦不好 罗蓝
Your dreams are bad, Roland
不是你
Not you
你是个好人
You're a good person
我打崔西
I hit Tracy
是因为你的梦你才打崔西
Your dreams make you hit Tracy
你知道怎么操作这些玩具  罗蓝
You know how to work this toy,Roland
拿来
Here
你看 你操作的玩具
You see, the way you work that toy
就好像发生在你身上一样
is like what's happening to you
你是太空船 罗蓝
You're the spaceship, Roland
你的梦想就是控制
And your dreams are the controls
谁
Who
谁来控制
Who runs the controls
你最近见过这个男人吗
Have you seen this man recently
来吧 亚瑟 我们跟罗蓝说再见
Come on, Arthur,we have to say bye-bye to Roland
再见
Bye
罗蓝
Roland
罗蓝 停止
Roland, stop
罗蓝
Roland
罗蓝必须留置观察
We need to keep Roland under observation
罗蓝
Roland
他要逃跑 罗蓝
- He's trying to get away  - Roland
罗蓝
Roland
诺勒特走了
Nollette's gone
我们应该安排保警去找他
We should arrange a security guard to find him
穆德 当你解释你的理论时
Mulder,no one's going to provide you with anything
没有人会认同的
once you explain how Roland Fuller
罗蓝怎会是凶手
is capable of these murders
你有个哥哥是吗 史卡利
You've got a brother,don't you, Scully
对 我有一个哥哥和一个弟弟
Yeah,I've got an older one and a younger one
有没有过正想打电话给其中一个
Have you ever thought about calling one of them,
突然他们就打给你
and then suddenly all of a sudden,the phone rings and it's one of them calling you
这样可以减低我的长途电话费吗
Does this pitch end with a way for me to lower my long-distance charges
我相信心灵相通
I believe in psychic connections
而且有证据显示
Evidence suggests suggests psychic connections are
家庭成员之间的 心灵相通更加强烈
stronger between family members
尤其是共用同一子宫的双胞胎
Particularly between twins that shared the same womb
好吧 也许是 但在这案子里
OK,maybe.But in this case
其中一个与冷冻箱更加相通
one sibling has closer ties to a frozen fudgsicle
多过与他的兄弟
than his own brother
亚瑟 葛瑞柏没有死
Arthur Grable is not dead
他处在一个回不来 但清醒的状态
He's in a state of consciousness no human has ever returned from
如果那状态启发了 一个人的心灵能力
What if that state allows one to develop psychic ability
那清醒的意识 太全神贯注
beyond the potential of the conscious mind
而得以发展或去相信
is too preoccupied to explore or believe in
或许就能用那种能力 来控制他的弟弟
He could use that to control his brother
去杀掉那些科学家
to kill the scientists
为什么  他们一起工作了好几年
But why he's been working with colleagues for years
这个问题 只有诺勒特博士能回答
That's a question only Dr.  Nollette can answer
好 我们走吧
OK  Let's go
我要给我哥哥电话
I have to call my brother
我们要找诺勒特
We've got to find Nollette
我们要跟保警谈谈
Let's talk to campus security
走这条路  不  左转
- We go this way   - No, we go left
好吧
Well
无论你在哪里 亚瑟
Wherever you are,Arthur,
我肯定你会喜欢这个
I'm sure you'll appreciate this
亚瑟和罗蓝 葛瑞柏
Arthur and Roland Grable,
出生在普吉教会医院
born at Puget Presbyterian
父母是路易斯 葛瑞柏夫妇
to Mr and Mrs Lewis Grable
日期是1952年6月15日
on July 15, 1952
亚瑟比罗蓝大四分钟
Arthur was four minutes older than Roland
一模一样的双胞胎
Identical twins
那表示他们是 单一卵子
Which means that they're the result of
和单一精子结合的成果
a single egg fertilised by a single sperm
我读过一些研究 在某些情况下
Studies suggest that in some cases
同卵双胞胎在胚胎期即形成
the identical twin arises early in the embryonic stage
而一个细胞的突变 导致拒绝另一个细胞
A mutation in one cell is rejected by other cells as foreign
所以罗蓝的情况
Roland's condition is the
就是因受拒于亚瑟的细胞
result of a damaged chromosome
导致染色体受损的结果
rejected by Arthur's cells
这也解释亚瑟的天才
In a way that would explain
及罗蓝的数学天赋
Arthur's genius and Roland's mathematical gift
有可能
In a way
史卡利探员
Agent Scully
我是冷藏基金会的赖瑞 贝灵顿
This is Larry Barrington at the Avalon Foundation
我们  这儿出现了点问题  啊  哈
- We've got a situation here  - Uh-huh
昨晚  有人闯入我们这里
Last night we had a break-in at the facility
没错
That's right
是亚瑟葛瑞柏的储存器
It's Arthur Grable's storage unit
他的恒温器受损
His thermostat's been compromised
有没有任何组织损坏
- Was there any tissue damage
我们正在评估
- We're trying to assess that now
温度不停地上升
The temperature's still rising
有些东西阻碍冷冻程序
Something's blocking our access to the cooling program
有人在亚瑟 葛瑞柏的冷藏箱做了手脚
Someone tampered with Arthur Grable's capsule
目前他们正试着稳定温度
They're attempting to stabilise it
诺勒特
Nollette
是
What
是什么
What is this
若我比其他人看得更远
If I have seen further than other men,
那是因为我站在巨人的肩膀上
it's because I have stood on the shoulders of giants
不
No
这不是你的
This isn't yours
不可思议
It's amazing
这个躯体坐在这儿  在我的面前说话
There's this body,sitting there in front of me,talking
是你在控制它  亚瑟
But you're controlling it, Arthur
你
You
偷了我的成果
took my work
你的工作对你有何好处
What good was your work going to do you
在你完成前
You died before you could finish it,
在你出版前你就死了
before you could publish it
那是我的成果
It was mine
也是个杰出的成果
and a brilliant piece of work too
当我看到白板上所写的
When I saw the writing on the board,
我就知道 有人发现关键所在
I knew someone had found the key
我们目标达到15马赫 我们的未来就有保证
Mach 15 was within our reach  Our futures were guaranteed
讽刺吗
Ironic, isn't it
你做出所有工作 而我获得所有的光荣
You did all the work, and I get all the glory
不要
No
要的
Yes
要的 亚瑟
Yes, Arthur
我来这里是解决问题
I was here, working on the intake problem,
在你袭击我时 问题正要解决
Moments away from a solution,when you attacked me
幸好 我有带手枪
Fortunately,I was carrying a gun
在我的同事被谋杀后 谁会怪我
After the murder of my colleagues,who could blame me
那  那真有趣
That's,that's interesting
我明白了
I've got it
那就是了
That's it
我明白了
I've got it
亚瑟
Arthur
亚瑟 开门
Arthur    Open the door
亚瑟
Arthur
怎样才能停下来  告诉我
How do you stop this   Tell me how
亚瑟
- Arthur  - Hey
罗蓝 我们需要你帮忙
Roland,we need you to help us
我们需要你的帮忙 去把这台机器停下来
Please,we need you to help us to stop the machine
努力想想看
Try to remember how
罗蓝 你要救他 不然他会死的
Roland,you've got to help him or he's going to die
挥手再见 亚瑟
Wave goodbye,Arthur
加油 罗蓝
- Come on,Roland
我想不起来
- I can't remember
他必须在监管下 做精神的评估
He'll be held in psychiatric custody for evaluation
他会被指控有罪吗
Is he being charged with a crime
检察官还没有决定
The DA hasn't made that determination yet
但我们推荐他让你监管
but we've recommended he be remanded
就等法官决定
to your custody as soon as the court allows it
怎么会这样
How could this happen
罗蓝从来没有暴力倾向
Roland never exhibited any violent tendencies
在我认为 这一切不是他的意志
It's my belief that he wasn't acting under his own volition
你是什么意思
What do you mean
这是亚瑟 葛瑞柏的杰作 罗蓝的哥哥
This is the work of Arthur,Roland's brother
这是推进器的新理论
It's a new theory of jet propulsion,
他死时仍未完成
unfinished at the time of his death
在过去的两周  罗蓝已经完成计算方程式
In the last two weeks, Roland has completed the calculations
怎么可能
How
我们不确定  史托迪太太
We're not sure,Mrs  Stodie
我们只知罗蓝在某种情况下
All we know is that Roland was somehow
完成了他哥哥的研究
able to finish his brother's research
罗蓝
Roland
你去哪里
Where are you going
罗蓝  不要走
Roland, don't go
我一定得走
I have to
好吧  再见
OK  bye
崔西
Tracy
等等
Wait
留着我的星星
Keep my stars
我爱你
I love you
我也是
Me,too